■
双语特效字幕
百度贴吧衣柜字幕组
专注GOT剧集 华语冰火最专业字幕
翻译     守誓剑
翻译    麻绳力攻
翻译    Bran的夏天
君临 King's Landing
红堡
Red Keep
翻译    Barossa
赫伦堡 Harrenhal
校对   北落师门
校对   临冬城的狮子
派
Pyke
克
城
派
Pyke
克
城
复校   ccxx  pksunking  Rhine
复校   杰诺斯·史林特  泰温公爵
临冬城 Winterfell
时间轴    poplar
后期   加文·维斯特林
策划   baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)
绝境长城 the Wall
最专业的华语冰火资料站：冰与火之歌中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
颤抖海 Shivering Sea
百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
魁尔斯Qarth
权力的游戏
第二季 第六集
衣柜字幕组
第六集  “新旧诸神”
"The Old Gods and New"
鲁温
临冬城学士
席恩·葛雷乔伊
我拿下了你的城堡
I've taken your castle.
- 席恩？  - 叫我席恩王子
- Theon?  - It's Prince Theon now.
达格摩
快起床 穿好衣服
Get up.  You have to get dressed.
我拿下了临冬城
I've taken Winterfell.
我拿下了它 占领了它
I took it. I'm occupying it.
布兰·史塔克
我的人用钩爪和绳索登上城墙
I sent men over the walls with grappling claws and ropes.
- 为什么？  - 因为要夺下城堡啊
- Why?  - To take the castle.
- 你和罗柏一起南下  - 之后他派我返回派克岛
- You went with Robb.  - And he sent me back to Pyke.
我是葛雷乔伊 不能同时为罗柏和我父亲而战
I'm a Greyjoy. I can't fight for Robb and my father both.
- 阿多在哪儿？  - 我不知道
- Where's Hodor?  - I don't know.
把那白痴找来
Find the Halfwit.
我的人会把你的人都带到院子里去
My men are bringing your people together in the courtyard.
为什么？
Why?
因为你和我要下去对他们讲话
So you and I can go down and tell them
- 告诉他们你已经把临冬城献给了我  - 我不会
- how you've yielded Winterfell to me.  - I won't.
不 你会的
Yes, you will.
我决不会 我决不投降
I won't.  I'll never yield.
我们会和你打 直到把你赶出去
We'll fight you and throw you out.
城堡是我的了
The castle is mine,
可人还是你的
but these people are still yours.
只有投降才能保他们平安
You'll yield to keep them safe,
保住他们的性命
to keep them alive.
这才是一个好领主该做的
That's what a good lord would do.
仔细掂量掂量你要说的话
Think carefully about what you want to say.
席恩
Theon.
难道你一直都这么恨我们？
Did you hate us the whole time?
我代表临冬城向席恩投降
I've yielded Winterfell to Theon.
大声点
Louder.
记得称我为席恩王子
Say Prince Theon.
我代表临冬城向席恩王子投降
I've yielded Winterfell to Prince Theon.
你们都认得我
You all know me.
是啊 我们都认得你这坨冒热气的大粪
Aye, we know you for a steaming sack of shit.
法兰 不要说话
Farlen, you be silent.
听你家小少爷的话 法兰
Listen to your little Lord, Farlen.
法兰
兽舍总管
他比你懂事
He has more sense than you do.
你们所有人都要服从他的命令
All of you should do as he commands.
我父亲已戴上海盐与磐石的古老王冠
My father has donned the ancient crown of salt and rock
加冕为铁群岛之王
and declared himself King of the Iron Islands.
作为征服者 他有权利归并整个北境
He claims the North as well by right of conquest.
你们都是他的臣民
You are all his subjects.
放屁 我只为史塔克家族服务
Bugger that. I serve the Starks.
如果你以为凭这一小撮王八蛋就能占领北――
If you think you can hold the North with this--
闭嘴！
Shut up!
只要像服侍奈德·史塔克一样忠心耿耿地为我服务
If you serve me as loyally as you served Ned Stark,
我会像他一样做你们的好领主
I  will be as good to you as he ever was.
谁怀有二心 我将让他痛不欲生
Betray me, and you will wish you hadn't.
鲁温学士 给派克送只信鸦
Maester Luwin, send a raven to Pyke
向父亲通报我在此的胜利
informing my father of my victory here
再送一只给我在深林堡的姐姐
and one to Deepwood Motte to my sister.
通知她率五百人前来临冬城
Inform her that she's to bring 500 men to Winterfell.
你是学城的学士
You are a Maester of the Citadel
立誓为临冬城公爵服务 不是吗？
sworn to serve the lord of Winterfell, are you not?
是的
I am.
布兰刚才已经告诉过你了
I am the Lord of Winterfell
现在的临冬城公爵就是我
as Bran just informed you.
送信鸦
Send the ravens.
是 大人
My Lord.
葛雷乔伊大人
My Lord Greyjoy.
你终于学会怎么和贵族说话了
I see you've finally learned how to address your betters.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
欧莎
我是这儿的俘虏
I was brought here a captive.
被捉那天您还在场呢
You were here the day I was taken.
是我捉到了你 那又怎样？
I'm the one who took you. What of it?
让我为您效劳吧
Let me serve you.
怎么效劳？
Serve me how?
我要战士 不要厨房里的荡妇
I need fighters, not kitchen sluts.
派我去厨房的是罗柏?史塔克
It was Robb Stark who put me in the kitchens.
请让我再度挥使长矛吧
Put a spear in my hand again.
然后让你把它插进我的脖子？
So you can bury it in my neck?
你当我是傻瓜么？
Do you take me for a fool?
起来
Get up.
滚一边去
Step aside.
为什么？
Why?
这就是你的梦 小主人
It's your dream, Little Lord.
海水淹没了这里
The ocean has come to swallow this place.
我不会被淹死的
I ain't letting it drown me.
- 几天之后——  - 葛雷乔伊！
- And in a few days' time--  - Greyjoy!
他们把他怎么了？
What have they done to him?
他正从托伦方城赶回来 结果被我们逮了个正着
We caught this one on his way back from Torrhen's Square.
为了缴他的械 我还折了两个人
Took out two of ours before I got his sword.
罗德利克爵士 很遗憾我们以敌人的身份重逢
Ser Rodrik, it grieves me that we meet as foes.
罗德利克·凯索
临冬城教头
更遗憾你看起来还不如后街的妓女更有荣誉感
It grieves me you've less honor than a back alley whore.
你在这片屋檐下长大
You were raised here under this roof.
- 这些都是你的同胞  - 他们不是我的同胞
- These people are your people.  - They are not my people.
罗柏国王待你亲如兄弟
King Robb thought of you as a brother.
我的兄弟们都死了
My brothers are dead.
战死在史塔克们手下 就像你这样的人手上
They died fighting Stark men, men like you.
是啊 他们战死于你父亲挑起的战争
Aye, they died fighting a war your father started.
史塔克大人将你和他自己的儿子一起养大
Lord Stark raised you among his own sons.
一起 但不是其中一员
Among them, but not one of them.
我是他抢来的人质
I was his hostage taken from my home.
如果他活着看到这一幕——
If he were alive to see this--
他看不到了 他已经死了
He's not. He's dead.
七国上下战火纷飞
The Seven Kingdoms are at war.
而临冬城是我的了
And Winterfell is mine.
我早该一剑刺穿你的肚子
I should have put a sword in your belly
而不是教你使剑
instead of in your hand.
你对史塔克家族忠心耿耿 老东西
You've served this House faithfully, old man.
但是如果你不闭嘴，我就要——
But keep talking and I'll--
把他带到牢里 锁起来——
Take him to the cells. Lock him up--
王子殿下
My prince,
不能饶了他 他必须付出代价
you cannot let that stand. He must pay.
他会一直在牢里烂成一滩——
I'll lock him in a cell until he rots--
不 他得赔付铁钱
No, he has to pay the iron price.
如果他活着 没人会看得起你
They'll never respect you while he lives.
罗德利克爵士
Ser Rodrik,
我判你死刑
I sentence you to death.
不！你说过如果我投降 他们都不会受到伤害
No! You said no harm would come to them if I yielded.
老东西管不住嘴巴
The old man couldn't keep his mouth shut.
请你不要草率决定
I urge you not to make a hasty decision.
他在我的部下面前侮辱我
He disrespected me in front of my men.
他自找的 与我无关
That was his decision, not mine.
他活着比死了更有价值
He is worth more to you alive than dead.
史塔克不会忘记
The Starks will pay.
求求你 席恩
Please, Theon,
仔细想想你在做什么
think what you do.
叫我席恩王子
You'll address me as Prince Theon
不然下一个死的就是你
or you'll be next.
带过来
Come.
不！
No!
- 不！  - 席恩！
- No!  - Theon!
求求你！
Please!
罗德利克爵士！
Ser Rodrik!
判决死刑的人必须亲自动手
He who passes the sentence should swing the sword.
- 求求你了！  - 懦夫
- I'm begging you!  - Coward.
停下！快停下！
Stop! Stop right now!
你没权力下命令了 小少爷
You don't give commands anymore, Little Lord.
- 求求你 停下来 求你阻止他  - 安静 孩子
- Please, stop this. Please stop him.  - Hush now, child.
我要去见你父亲了
I'm off to see your father.
你保证过不会伤害他们！
You said no harm would come!
你保证过不会伤害他们 席恩 求求你
You said no harm would come. Theon, please.
还有什么要说的 老东西？
Any last words, old man?
愿诸神指引你 席恩·葛雷乔伊
Gods help you, Theon Greyjoy.
你已经彻底迷失了
Now you are truly lost.
席恩 别 不要！
Theon, please, don't.
- 谁来阻止他啊  - 我什么都愿意做 求你了！
- Do something.  - I'll do anything. Please!
不 求求你 不要这样！
No, please, stop it!
白灵 跟紧了
Ghost, stay with us.
白灵！
Ghost!
你的宠物跑了
There goes your pet.
它不是宠物
He's not a pet.
是的 它不是
You're right, he's not.
野物不能被驯养
You can't tame a wild thing.
也不能被信任
You can't trust a wild thing.
- 白灵不一样  - 那是你的想法
- Ghost is different.  - So you think.
野物有它们自己的准则
Wild creatures have their own rules,
自己的心智
their own reasons.
你永远不可能了解它们
And you'll never know them.
现在我们要找的野人
Now the wildlings we're looking for
白天睡觉 夜晚打猎
sleep during the day and hunt at night.
琼恩·雪诺
守夜人侍从
科林
“断掌” 守夜人游骑兵
你刚才说野物不可能被了解
I thought you said you couldn't know wild things.
我是说你不能
I said you can't.
太阳升起 他们便找个洞穴藏身
They find a nice cave to hide in while the sun's up
夜晚到来 他们就开始杀戮
and do their killing when it's dark.
- 我们也可以这样做  - 不 我们不行
- We could do the same.  - No, we couldn't.
这是他们的国度
This is their country.
他们了解何处可行 何处不可行
They know where to walk, where not to walk.
曾经我有几个好兄弟就是这么掉进冰隙里
I've lost good men who fell into a crevasse
没踩进去他们一点也没发觉
they didn't see till they were in it.
父亲总说我来自北境
My father always said I'm of the North.
- 我可不是玩笑   - 看看周围 小子
- I wasn't joking. - Look around, boy.
这里看起来像家乡么？
This look like home to you?
你若是以为自己了解这里 那你就危险了
You start thinking you know this place, it'll kill you.
明白吗？
You understand me?
不 你不明白
No, you don't.
我们在打仗
We're at war.
我们一直都在打仗
We've always been at war.
这场战争永远没有尽头 因为我们面对的不是人
It's never going to end 'cause we're not fighting an enemy.
而是真正的北方 而北方是我们无法征服的
We're fighting the North and it's not going anywhere.
守夜人的身份对你来说是件幸事
The Watch has given you a great gift.
作为报答 你只需献出一件东西
You only have one thing to give in return--
你的生命
your life.
我很乐意奉献自己的生命
I'll gladly give my life.
我不想让你“乐意”奉献生命
I don't want you to be glad about it.
我要你声嘶力竭地战斗
I want you to curse and fight
直到你的心脏停止跳动
until your heart's done pumping.
而且记住 孩子--
And know this, boy--
你为南方人献出生命
your death will be a gift for them south of the Wall.
但是他们永远不会知道你的作为
They'll never know what you've done.
不会知道你是怎么死的
They'll never know how you died.
甚至不可能知道你的名字
They won't even know your damn name,
但正因为你这个无名杂种在长城外丢了性命
but they'll be alive because some nameless bastard
他们才能活下来
north of the Wall gave his life for theirs.
现在 你明白了吗？
Now, do you understand me?
嗯
I do.
你比脸上看起来还要沉闷
You're even dumber than you look.
孩子 这些话只是说一说
It's just words, boy,
让我们在夜里能感到温暖些
to keep us a little warmer in the night,
觉得自己不是在白费工夫
make us feel like we've got a purpose.
来吧
Come on.
我们得在夜幕降临前找到那些混账野人
We've got to find these goat fuckers
否则他们会抓到我们
before night falls and they find us.
- 你识字么？   - 大人？
- Can you read? - My Lord?
泰温·兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵 西境守护
你识字么？
Can you read?
亚摩利·洛奇
爵士
这封详述了我们步兵动向的信
This letter detailing our infantry movements
本应送到马尔布兰家的戴蒙爵士手里
was meant for Lord Damon of House Marbrand.
却送给了多曼家的马林爵士
It was sent to Lord Marlyn of House Dormand.
非常抱歉 大人 我一定是--
My apologies, My Lord. I must have--
姑娘 把那本《七国主要贵族之世家谱系与历史》递给我
Girl, fetch me the "History of the Greater and the Lesser Houses."
就在那上面--
It's the one on the--
我的侍酒识字都比你强
My cupbearer can read better than you.
这个多曼家族是向谁效忠的？
To whom does House Dormand owe allegiance?
大人 我--
My Lord, I--
效忠于临冬城的史塔克家族！
To the Starks of Winterfell!
艾莉亚·史塔克
泰温的侍酒
他们有两万兵力 而且囚禁着我的儿子！
Who have 20,000 men and my son!
本来觉得除了虐待村民之外
I judged you might be good for something more
你还能有点用处
than brutalizing peasants.
看来我高估你了
I see I overestimated you.
要是你胆敢再拿我儿子的命开玩笑 我就……
If you ever put my son's life at risk again, I'll...
下去
Leave us.
姑娘 把书放回去
Put the book away, girl.
也许我们下一场战斗该让你来出谋划策
Maybe you should devise our next battle plan while you're about it.
- 培提尔·贝里席伯爵到了   - 嗯
- Lord Petyr Baelish. - Hmmm.
都退下
Give us the room.
收拾干净啊
Clear all this.
- 泰温公爵   - 贝里席
- Lord Tywin. - Baelish.
培提尔·贝里席
“小指头”  财政大臣
- 喝酒？   -谢谢
- Wine? - Thank you.
君临有什么消息么？
What news from the capital?
我是直接从蓝礼·拜拉席恩的营地过来的
I travelled here directly from Renly Baratheon's camp.
啊 先王蓝礼
Ah, the late king Renly.
好一个短命国王
Rather a short reign.
听说是被个女人谋杀的
Murdered by a woman, I hear.
是有人这么说
So they say.
也有人说这事情颇有些蹊跷
There has been talk of other forces at work,
也许是某种黑暗的力量作祟
dark forces.
倒酒
Here.
当雄心壮志受挫的时候
Men love to blame demons
人们总喜欢把责任归咎于魔鬼
when their grand plans unravel.
我相信混乱的时局
It is my belief that a moment of chaos
总是会带来转瞬即逝的机遇
affords opportunities lost soon after.
你以为只有你想到了么？
You say that as if you were the first man alive to think it.
不用你说 危机也是机遇
Yes, a crisis is an opportunity.
你今天来还有什么深刻见解想要对我说的？
What other brilliant insights have you brought me today?
除了兰尼斯特和史塔克家族
After the Lannisters and the Starks,
提利尔家族的军事力量最强大
the Tyrells command the largest host.
他们有七国里最肥沃的土地
Their lands are the most fertile in the Seven Kingdoms,
- 兵强马壮 - 是啊 是啊 是啊
- feeding horses and soldiers. - Yes, yes, yes.
蓝礼死后 提利尔还未效忠其他国王
The Tyrells have not yet declared for any of the surviving kings.
洛拉斯想要复仇 他把蓝礼的死算在史坦尼斯头上
Loras wants revenge. He blames Stannis for Renly's death.
而玛格丽她--
And Margaery--
她想当王后
Wants to be queen.
是的 王后
Yes, she does.
提利尔家族曾举兵反抗铁王座
House Tyrell rebelled against the Iron Throne,
- 反抗我的外孙   - 话虽如此
- against my grandson. - They did.
不过等到史坦尼斯和罗柏·史塔克
And perhaps that treason should be punished
都被剿灭
one day,
再跟他们算账不迟
after Stannis and Robb Stark are defeated.
给贝里席伯爵多倒些酒
More wine for Lord Baelish.
如果您委托我代表您的家族利益
If you will allow me to represent your family's interests,
我相信可以和他们定下有利的协议--
I believe that an advantageous agreement--
提利尔家的部队已经回到高庭了么？
The Tyrell host has returned to Highgarden?
是的
They have.
对不起 大人
Pardon, My Lord.
没事 洒点酒而已
It's only wine.
你要亲自去么？
You would ride there yourself?
您批准的话 今晚就去
Tonight, with your leave.
我会在天黑前给出答复
I'll have an answer by nightfall.
姑娘 不用擦了
That'll be all, girl.
还有什么事？
What else?
奉令郎提利昂之命
On your son Tyrion's directive,
我去见了凯特琳·史塔克
I met with Catelyn Stark.
见她做什么？
Why?
替令郎提一项颇为有趣的建议给她
He had an interesting proposal for her
- 和她的女儿们有关   - 嗯
- concerning her daughters. - Hmm.
- 女的   - 野人
- A girl. - A wildling.
我们可以拷问她
We could question her.
你尽管问
You could.
她可不会回答你
She won't answer.
我见过一个野人宁可咬舌自尽头也不回答问题
I've known a wildling to bite off his tongue instead of talking.
- 你叫什么？  - 耶哥蕊特
- What's your name? - Ygritte.
你靠近她时 她正要去抓斧头
She was reaching for this axe when you got to her.
你若慢半拍 早被她砍翻
Give her half a chance, she'll bury it in your face.
耶哥蕊特
“火吻而生”
我给你讲了名字
I gave you my name.
我是琼恩·雪诺
I'm Jon Snow.
你们得火葬死者
You ought to burn them you killed.
这点火不够火葬
We'd need a big fire for that.
告诉我 耶哥蕊特
Tell me, Ygritte,
为什么让我们升起大火？
why do you want us to build a big fire?
附近还有你的野人朋友 对吧？
Are there some more friends in the area?
烧了他们 除非你想再杀一次
Burn them or maybe you'll need those swords again.
这孩子已经杀过一个死人
Our boy here's already killed one dead man.
要是得再杀一次他也能做到
He can do it again if he has to.
峡谷那边有什么？
What waits beyond the pass?
- 自由民   - 有多少？
- The Free Folk. - How many?
几百几千呢
Hundreds and thousands.
包你大开眼界 乌鸦
More than you've ever seen, Crow.
你们为什么在那儿集合？
Why come to the mountains?
你的国王到霜雪之牙做什么？
What's in the frostfangs your king could want?
你们打算进军长城？
Do you mean to march on the Wall?
女孩 知道我是谁？
Do you know who I am, girl?
断掌科林
Qhorin Halfhand.
说实话
Tell me true.
要是我落到你们手里
If your people captured me,
他们会抓我作俘虏么？
would they take me prisoner?
要是他们善心大发
They'd take your head off your shoulders
会把你脑袋剁下来
if they was feeling kind.
要是心情不好 会慢慢将你折磨致死
If not, they'd kill you slow.
我们没有多余的食物
We have no food for her.
更不可能分配人力看守她
Can't spare a man to watch her.
不能放她走 她会把曼斯·雷德的军队带过来的
Can't let her go. She'll bring Mance Rayder's army down on us.
必须要这样做
It needs to be done.
- 要我动手么？  -别
- Want me to do it? - No.
不 我来
No, I'll do it.
走吧 兄弟们
Come, brothers.
这儿交给他了
We'll leave him to it.
我们在山顶会合
We'll meet you at the top.
别耽误太久
Don't take too long.
我们可是在他们的地盘上
We're deep in their country now.
你没杀过女人 对不对？
You never killed a woman before, did you?
你不必杀我
You don't need to do it.
曼斯会收留你 我知道他会
Mance would take you. I know he would.
这里有秘密通路
There's secret ways.
那些乌鸦永远抓不到我们
The Crows would never catch us.
我和他们一样都是乌鸦
I'm as much a Crow as they are.
之后 你会...
Will you burn me...
烧了我？
after?
我做不到
Can't.
烟雾会被发现
Someone might see the smoke.
狠狠地 照准了斩
Strike hard and true,
琼恩·雪诺
Jon Snow,
不然我做鬼也来找你
or I'll come back and haunt you.
好冷
That's cold.
快
Go on.
动手吧
Be quick about it.
动手
Do it.
私生子啊 快动手！
Bastard, do it!
你下不了手 你我都清楚
You can't do it. We both know it.
太阳要落山了 琼恩·雪诺
The sun's going down, Jon Snow.
你的朋友早不见踪影了
And your friends are nowhere close.
我会找到他们的
I'll find them.
那就喊他们来吧 快点
Call for them go on.
大声喊
Call loudly.
愿七神指引公主的旅途
May the Seven guide the princess on her journey.
愿圣母赐予她健康
May the mother give her health.
愿老妪赐予她智慧
May the crone give her wisdom.
愿战士赐予她勇气
May the warrior give her courage.
会有一天 我祈祷你爱上某个人
One day I pray you love someone.
我会祈祷 你如此爱她
I pray you love her so much,
以至于当你闭上眼睛 还能看见她的脸庞
when you close your eyes, you see her face.
这是我对你的愿望
I want that for you.
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔” 代理首相
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
摄政太后
我要让你知道 爱一个人是什么样的感觉
I want you to know what it's like to love someone,
真正地爱着一个人
to truly love someone,
然后我便把她从你身边夺走
before I take her from you.
托曼·拜拉席恩
王子
乔佛里·拜拉席恩
国王
珊莎·史塔克
你就像一只小猫一样 喵喵地呼唤它妈妈
You sound like a little cat mewling for his mother.
王子才不会哭
Princes don't cry.
- 我见过你哭   - 你刚才说什么了么 小姐？
- I saw you cry. - Did you say something, My Lady?
我离开临冬城那天我弟弟哭了
My little brother cried when I left Winterfell.
那又怎样？
So?
所以哭泣很正常
It seems a normal thing.
你弟弟是王子么？
Is your little brother a prince?
不是
No.
那就别告诉我王子该不该哭
Not really relevant, then, is it?
马林·特兰
御林铁卫
桑铎·克里冈
“猎狗” 御林铁卫
过来 狗儿
Come, dog.
乔佛里万岁！
Hail, Joffrey!
- 国王万岁
- Hail to the king.
七神保佑你 陛下
Seven blessings on you, Your Grace.
凶手！杂种！
Murderer! Bastard!
国王万岁
All hail the king.
他不是国王 他是乱伦的杂种！
He's no king. He's a bastard!
求您了 陛下 我们饿极了
Please, Your Grace, we're hungry.
-小魔猴!  - 快把王子带回城堡
- Freak!  - Get the prince back to the keep now.
是的 大人 快 跟上
Yes, My Lord. Come, quickly.
求您了 陛下 给我们点吃的吧！
Please, Your Grace, give us some food!
面包 陛下 求求您了！
Bread, Your Grace, please!
谁扔的？
Who threw that?
给我把这人交出来
I want the man who threw that.
找到这个人 把他带过来!
Find who did that and bring him to me!
- 站稳! - 挡着他们!
- Hold on! - Hold them back!
杀了他们! 把他们全给我杀了!
Just kill them! Kill them all!
- 走 快走! - 撤退!
- Move. Move! - Pull back!
把他撕成碎片!
Tear him to pieces!
你们在干什么? 我要处死这些人!
What are you doing? I want these people executed!
他们也想对你这么做
And they want the same for you.
珊莎在哪儿?
Where's Sansa?
到门这边!
Through the door!
过来!
Come on!
保护国王!
Protect the king!
- 回去! - 后退!
- Get back! - Fall back!
- 快走! - 回城门那儿!
- Move! - To the gates!
- 进来!进来! -保护好他!
- Come in! Come in! - Keep him safe!
- 臭婊子!
- Motherfucker!
- 小心 挡住他们 - 过来
- Watch out. Hold them back. - Come on.
嘿!
Hey!
一群叛徒!
Traitors!
我要把他们的头通通砍掉
I'll have all their heads.
你这瞎了眼的大蠢货!
Oh, you blind, bloody fool.
你没权利冒犯我
You can't insult me.
我们有过暴君也有过庸王
We've had vicious kings and we've had idiot kings,
但是我们还从来没有倒霉到有你这样
but I don't know if we've ever been cursed with
又残暴又愚蠢的国王
a vicious idiot for a king.
- 你怎么能——  - 我当然能,我就这样
- You can't--  - I can, I am.
他们攻击我!
They attacked me!
他们往你身上扔牛粪 你就要把他们都杀光?
They threw a cow pie at you, so you decided to kill them all?
他们在挨饿 你这笨蛋
They're starving, you fool.
一切皆因你引发的这场战争
All because of a war you started.
你在和国王说话!
You're talking to a king!
我还打了国王
And now I've struck a king.
我的手从手腕上掉下来了吗?
Did my hand fall from my wrist?
史塔克家的女孩呢?
Where is the Stark girl?
愿他们带走她吧
Let them have her.
如果她死了 你就永远也见不到你詹姆舅舅了
If she dies, you'll never get your Uncle Jaime back.
你可欠着他相当多呢 你知道么
You owe him quite a bit, you know.
你要去哪儿?
Where are you going?
你被操过吗 小姑娘?
You ever been fucked, little girl?
来这儿
Come here.
带几个人去把史塔克家的女孩找来
Take some men and go and find the Stark girl.
我只接受国王的命令
I take my orders from the king.
这边!
This way!
求你们!
Please!
不 不
No, no.
求你!
Please!
没事儿了 小小鸟
You're all right now, little bird.
都过去了
You're all right.
- 没事了 没事了  - 在这边
- We'll get you. We'll get you. - This way.
你受伤了吗 小姐?
Are you hurt, My Lady?
小小鸟在流血
The little bird's bleeding.
来几个人带她回笼子里
Someone take her back to her cage,
治疗一下伤口
see to that cut.
干得好 克里冈
Well done, Clegane.
我又不是为了你
I didn't do it for you.
他不该让我等着
He shouldn't make me wait.
香料之王是全魁尔斯第二富有的人
The Spice King is the second wealthiest man in Qarth.
所有人都得等着他
He makes everyone wait.
札罗·赞旺·达梭斯
魁尔斯“十三巨子”之一
丹妮莉丝·坦格里安
风暴降生 龙之母
当然 你本可以避免这样的尴尬
Of course, you could have avoided this embarrassment
只要你嫁给魁尔斯第一富有的人
if you married the wealthiest man in Qarth.
我已经有丈夫了
I already have a husband.
卓戈卡奥已经不在了 卡丽熙
Khal Drogo is gone, Khaleesi.
您这么年轻 又这么美丽
You are far too young to be a widow forever
不该做一辈子寡妇
and far too beautiful.
你聪明过头了
And you are far too smart
以为我会被这些花言巧语说服
to think that I will succumb to flattery.
我活了这样一大把年纪
I have travelled very far in my life
可以算得上阅女无数了
and met many women,
但没有一个对花言巧语不感冒的
but none that are immune to flattery.
- 龙之母!  - 噢
- The Mother of Dragons!  - Ah.
他来了
Here he comes.
请您原谅 我昨晚做了噩梦
Forgive me. I had terrible dreams last night.
可怕的噩梦
Terrible dreams.
直到太阳已开始照耀 小鸟已开始鸣叫
I could not sleep until the sun was shining
我都未曾入睡
and the birds were singing.
洗去红色荒原的旅尘后
Look what a beauty you are
你是多么漂亮一个可人儿啊
now the Red Waste has been washed off you.
我对先前所有的不愉快感到抱歉
I am sorry about all that unpleasantness.
一位真正的银发坦格利安
The silver hair of a true Targaryen.
札罗·赞旺·达梭斯 对于从码头爬出来的你来说
Xaro Xhoan Daxos, she is far too lovely
她太过于可爱了
for a glorified dockworker like yourself.
是啊 但是他们说你祖父,
Very true, and yet they say that your grandfather,
仅靠一辆马车贩卖胡椒
who sold pepper off the back of a wagon,
却最终娶到了一位远比他可爱并且出身高贵的女士
married a lady far lovelier and higher born than himself.
世上任何一位女士
Every lady alive was lovelier
都比我祖父要可爱并且出身高贵
and higher born than my grandfather.
啊嗯
Ahem.
我的仆人难道没给你们提供些吃的喝的?
Did my servants not offer you something to eat, to drink?
我该让他们在广场受鞭刑
I'll have them flogged in the square.
实在感谢 大人 您待客十分宽厚
Thank you, My Lord. You are a gracious host,
但却没有一位仆人能带来我想要的
but there is no servant alive that can bring me what I want.
噢 她说戏可很有天赋 就凭这一点
Oh, she has a talent for drama, this one.
那么 我的小公主 你想要的是什么呢?
So, my little princess, what is it you want?
生来就属于我的——
My birthright--
维斯特洛的七大王国
the Seven Kingdoms of Westeros.
我恐怕这件事情上我还不如一位仆人
I fear I'm no better than a servant in this regard.
我没法给你我没有的东西
I cannot give you what I do not have.
我向你要的不是王国
I'm not asking you for the Kingdoms.
我向你要的是船
I'm asking you for ships.
我需要渡过狭海
I need to cross the Narrow Sea.
我同样需要我的船
I need my ships as well.
你也知道 我要用他们
I use them, you see,
载着香料奔波于一个又一个港口
to bring spices from one port to another.
待我夺回铁王座
Whatever you grant me now will be repaid
你所给予我的任何东西我都三倍奉还
three times over when I retake the Iron Throne.
夺回？
Retake?
你以前坐过铁王座吗?
Did you once sit on the Iron Throne?
我父亲被杀害之前曾坐在上面
My father sat there before he was murdered.
但如果你自己未曾坐在上面的话
But if you did not sit on it yourself,
难道不应该纠正为夺取吗?
would it not be correct to say take the Iron Throne?
我不是来这里辩论语法问题的
I didn't come here to argue grammar.
当然不 你是来夺取我的船的
Of course not. You came to take my ships.
那么让我说明一下我的观点
So let me explain my position,
小公主
little princess.
我可没你那么好的家世
Unlike you, I do not have exalted ancestors.
我要靠贸易谋生
I make my living by trade.
依照利润来判断每一笔交易
And I judge every trade on its merits.
你要船
You ask for ships.
你说我能得到三倍的回报
You say I shall be repaid triple.
我并非怀疑您的诚实或是意图
I do not doubt your honesty or your intentions.
但是在您偿还这笔债之前
But before you repay your debts,
你必须攻下七大王国
you must seize the Seven Kingdoms.
- 你有军队吗?  - 还没
- Do you have an army?  - Not yet.
你连军队都没有
You do not have an army.
那你在维斯特洛有强大的盟友吗?
Do you have powerful allies in Westeros?
维斯特洛有许多人支持我的事业
There are many there that support my claim.
你上次在那里是什么时候?
When were you there last?
我还是个婴儿的时候就离开那里了
I left when I was a baby.
那么 实话说 就是没有盟友了
So, in truth, you have no allies.
待我回归 人们会揭竿而起
The people will rise to fight for their rightful
为他们合法的女王而战
Queen when I return.
啊
Ah.
请您原谅 我的小公主
Forgive me,little princess,
我可不能仅仅为了愿望和梦想就投下巨资
but I cannot make an investment based on wishes and dreams.
现在请您允许我离开
Now if you'll pardon me.
你可知道潘托斯的总督 伊利里欧·莫帕提斯?
Do you know Illyrio Mopatis,Magister of Pentos?
是的 我们见过面 一个狡猾的人
Yes, we've met.A shrewd man.
在我的婚礼上他给了我三颗龙蛋化石
For my wedding he gave me three petrified dragon eggs.
他相信——整个世界都相信——
He believed--the world believed--
岁月已经将它们化作了石头
that the ages had turned them to stone.
敢问已有多少世纪人们未曾看到过龙在天空中翱翔?
How many centuries has it been since dragons roamed the skies?
但我梦见过 梦见如果我带着这些龙蛋
But I dreamt that if I carried those eggs
步入一场熊熊烈火当中,它们便会孵化
into a great fire, they would hatch.
当我真的步入那场火中 我的子民以为我疯了
When I stepped into the fire, my own people thought I was mad.
但是当火焰燃尽
But when the fire burned out,
我却毫发无伤
I was unhurt,
这就是龙之母
the Mother of Dragons.
你明白了吗？
Do you understand?
我并非寻常女子
I'm no ordinary woman.
我的梦想终会成真
My dreams come true.
我十分欣赏你的热情
I admire your passion.
但在商业上 我更相信逻辑 而非热情
But in business, I trust in logic, not passion.
我很抱歉 小公主
I'm sorry, little princess.
我可不是你的小公主
I am not your little princess.
我是风暴降生丹妮莉丝 有着古老的瓦雷利亚血统
I am Daenerys Stormborn of the blood of old Valyria
我会夺得属于我的东西
and I will take what is mine.
夺得他们 用血与火
With fire and blood, I will take it.
好吧 女士 但别用我的船
Yes, My Lady, but not with my ships.
谁教你识字的?
Who taught you to read?
我父亲 大人
My father, My Lord.
嗯
Hmm.
我也教过我儿詹姆认字
I taught my son Jaime to read.
有一天学士来找我
The Maester came to me one day,
跟我说他没有学
told me he wasn't learning.
他记不住字母
He couldn't make sense of the letters.
拼写什么的一团糟
He reversed them in his head.
学士说他听过这种怪病
The Maester said he'd heard tell of this affliction
建议我们只能听之任之
and that we simply must accept it.
哈!
Ha!
在那之后 我让詹姆
After that, I sat Jaime down
每天练字四小时 直到学会为止
for four hours every day until he learned.
他因此而恨过我 一段时间
He hated me for it, for a time.
很长一段时间
For a long time,
但他学会了
but he learned.
你父亲在哪儿? 还活着吗?
Where is your father? Is he alive?
他是干什么的?
Who was he?
是个石匠
A stonemason.
会认字的石匠?
A stonemason who could read?
- 嗯  - 他自学的
- Hmm.  - He taught himself.
有点骨气
Quite a man.
是什么害了他?
What killed him?
忠诚
Loyalty.
你可真是个舌尖嘴利的小东西 嗯?
You're a sharp little thing, aren't you?
请问……
Did...
抱歉 大人 我不该问问题的
Forgive me, My Lord. I shouldn't ask questions.
是不该……
No...
但你已经问了开头
But you've already begun.
你了解你的父亲吗 大人?
Did you know your father, My Lord?
当然
I did.
是他伴我长大
I grew up with him.
我看着他一点点变老
I watched him grow old.
他很疼爱我们
He loved us.
他是个好人
He was a good man,
但也是一个懦夫
but a weak man,
一个差点毁了家族名誉的懦夫
a weak man who nearly destroyed our House and name.
我觉得冷了
I'm cold.
我去为火堆添点柴 大人
I'll fetch more wood for the fire, My Lord.
……的一万大军正在西征……
……金牙城。估计本周之内就将接近你部…（据探子来报）
……罗柏·史塔克的军队正在向南部海岸行进。请立即警告
……沙略特伯爵，务必坚守银山城，以防其东进
你去哪儿 女孩？
Where are you going, girl?
军械库 大人
The armory, My Lord.
为什么？
Why?
泰温大人命我去的
Lord Tywin sent me.
这是什么？
What might this be?
泰温大人给的
Lord Tywin gave it to me.
干嘛用的
What for?
他让我拿到军械库去
To take to the armory.
他干嘛要这样做？
Why would he do that?
走 我们去问问
Let's go and ask him.
走开！
Move!
让开！
Get out of the way!
贾昆·赫加尔
亚摩利·洛奇
Amory Lorch.
女孩给了我第二个名字
A girl has named a second name.
某人定会完成任务
A man will do what must be done.
现在就去！
Now!
女孩不能限定时间
A girl cannot tell a man when exactly he must do a thing.
时辰未到 某人不能下手
A man cannot make a thing happen before its time.
但是他要去通知泰温了 他已经走了
But he's going to tell Tywin. He's getting away.
就是现在
It has to be now.
卫兵！
Guard!
- 陛下  - 陛下
- Your Grace.  - Your Grace.
尊敬的陛下
My honor, Your Grace.
罗柏·史塔克
北境之王
陛下
Your Grace.
－陛下  －昆特
- Your Grace.  - Quent.
特蕾莎
瓦兰提斯战地医生
泰丽莎小姐
Lady Talisa.
陛下
Your Grace.
我不确定我能否被称为小姐
I'm not sure I'm a lady.
我还不是很熟悉维斯特洛的风俗
Westerosi customs are still a bit foreign to me.
那些庞杂的规则的确难以记忆
It's hard to keep all the rules straight.
不过若我没记错的话
But if I remember my lessons,
贵族出身的女性通常被称作小姐
a woman of noble birth is always called a lady
除非 她是女王 或者公主
unless she's a queen or a princess.
我可以找到了解这些的人
I could find someone who knows.
你觉得我是贵族出身？
Why are you so sure I'm of noble birth?
这很明显
Because it's obvious.
如果我告诉你我父亲是在桥边卖鞋带的小贩
What if I told you my father sold lace on the long bridge
而我和母亲兄弟一起住在我们的商店上面呢？
and my mother, my brother, and I lived with him above our shop?
那我会称您是骗子
I'd call you a liar.
一个真正的贵族可不会指责淑女的不实
Not very noble to accuse a lady of dishonesty.
我一直认为我是个骗术高手
I always thought I was a brilliant liar.
恐怕还是您的截肢技术更高明一些
Better at amputations, I'm afraid.
真是个漂亮的地方
Quite a pretty spot.
我们会在这里停留很久么？
Will we be here long?
我不能跟您讨论关于军队行进的问题
I couldn't really discuss troop movements with you.
我又不是奸细
I'm not a spy.
奸细当然会否认自己的身份了
Of course a spy would deny being a spy.
说得没错 被你发现了
You're right. You've found me out.
我在给兰尼斯特写信
I'm writing a letter to the Lannisters.
“少狼主正在进军”
"The young wolf is on the move."
或许你能与我们同行……
Perhaps you'd join me...
当然 如果你有空的话 呃……
If you've got time,of course, for, well...
罗柏
Robb.
母亲
Mother.
母亲 这是泰丽莎小姐
Mother, this is Lady Talisa.
凯特琳·徒利
史塔克夫人
她一直在照顾伤员
She's been helping with the wounded.
她非常的……乐于助人
She's been very...helpful.
泰丽莎小姐
Lady Talisa.
史塔克夫人
Lady Stark.
泰丽莎小姐……？
Lady Talisa...?
－梅吉尔  －梅吉尔
- Maegyr.  - Maegyr?
请原谅 我从未听说过这个姓氏
Forgive me,I do not know this name.
这姓氏在这里并不常见 这是瓦兰提斯的古老姓氏
An uncommon name here. An old name in Volantis.
请原谅 夫人 陛下
Excuse me, My Lady. Your Grace.
我好想你
I've missed you.
是啊 你看起来不大自在
Yes, you look positively forlorn.
还不是因为你突然出现
You surprised me, that's all.
真没想到今天就能见到你
I didn't think I'd see you today.
我希望你能自由自在地生活
I wish that you were free to follow your heart.
我知道
I know.
但你继承了你父亲的责任心
You have inherited your father's responsibilities.
而这意味着代价
I'm afraid they come at a cost.
－我明白  －你已经订过婚了——
- I know.  - You are promised to another--
一项应尽的义务
a debt that must be paid.
－我没忘  －陛下
- I haven't forgotten.  - Your Grace.
卢斯·波顿
恐怖堡伯爵
夫人 临冬城来信
My Lady.News from Winterfell.
你兄弟抛弃你了？
Your brothers desert you?
我可以为你指条明路
I can tell you which way to go.
我们要在这里扎营
We'll stop here.
天色太黑了 难以前行
Too dark to go any farther today.
这？这里无处安身
Here? There's no shelter here.
哪里都无处安身
There's no shelter anywhere.
会有的 如果你知道如何寻找
There is if you know where to look.
我们会死于严寒的
The cold could kill us both.
- 如果能生堆火——  - 不能生火
- If you light a fire--  - No fire.
- 但是火能——  －不能生火
- But a fire is-- - No fire.
好吧 随你便
Have it your way.
靠近点 我们才能保暖
We'll stay warmer if we stay close.
咱们俩里面肯定是你先冻死
Bet you freeze to death before I do.
我赌你的命
Bet your life.
你觉得他们出来找你了？
Think they're out looking for you?
－是的  －你觉得他们会找到你？
- Yes.- Think they'll find you?
是的
Yes.
你可真勇敢
You're brave.
愚蠢
Stupid,
但是勇敢
but brave.
天一亮我们就出发 先睡会儿
We start again at first light. Get some sleep.
别动
Stop moving.
我只是想找个舒服的姿势
I'm just trying to get comfortable.
停！
Stop it!
－你还动！ －我有么？
-You're still moving.  - Was I?
我没注意啊
I didn't notice that time.
这不可能是真的
This cannot be true.
我们接到了从白港
We've had ravens from White Harbor,
荒冢屯 和 恐怖堡 的来信
Barrowton and the Dreadfort.
恐怕这是真的
I'm afraid it is true.
为什么？为什么席恩会——
Why? Why would Theon--
因为葛雷乔伊家都是叛逆的婊子
Because the Greyjoys are treasonous whores.
- 我的弟弟们呢？  －我们还没有他们的消息
- My brothers?  - We've heard nothing of them.
但是我们收到了罗德利克·凯索的死讯
But Rodrik Cassel is dead.
我早就说过 永远不要相信葛雷乔伊！
I told you, never trust a Greyjoy!
我必须立刻返回北境
I must go North at once.
战事未尽 陛下
There's still a war to win, Your Grace.
要是连自家城堡都守不住
我这是哪门子的国王？
How can I call myself king if I can't hold my own castle?
我要如何得到部下的追随，当自己连——
How can I ask men to follow me if I can't--
你是个国王
You are a king.
这意味着你不必事必躬亲
And that means you don't have to do everything yourself.
让我去与席恩谈判
Let me go and talk to Theon.
不会有和谈的 他必将为此付出生命的代价
There will be no talk. He will die for this.
席恩守城的人寥寥无几
Theon holds the castle with a skeleton crew.
我会给在恐怖堡的私生子捎个信
Let me send word to my bastard at the Dreadfort.
他能带领几百人在新月之前夺回临冬城
He can raise a few hundred men and retake Winterfell before the new moon.
我们还要对付兰尼斯特
We have the Lannisters on the run.
如果现在回师北境 那就前功尽弃了
If you march all the way back north now, you'll lose what you gained.
我儿子会很荣幸为您带回席恩的脑袋
My boy would be honored to bring you Prince Theon's head.
告诉你儿子 布兰和瑞肯的人身安全才是最重要的
Tell your son Bran and Rickon's safety is paramount.
至于席恩——我希望能活捉他
And Theon-- I want him brought to me alive.
我想盯着他的双眼 问他为什么要这样做
I want to look him in the eye and ask him why.
然后我将亲自将他斩首
And then I'll take his head myself.
我怎么会相信你这样野人小骗子呢？
Why on earth would I trust the word of a lying little savage like you?
我才没有说谎
I'm no liar.
野人不是骗子就是蛮子
All wildlings are liars and savages
没有任何忠诚可言
with no loyalty to anything or anyone.
我只是为了活命罢了
I done what I had to do to stay alive.
我跟你一样憎恨史塔克
I hate the Starks as well as you do.
让我来服侍您吧 大人
Let me serve you, My Lord.
你要怎么做？别跟我说你手能持矛 为我战斗
How? And don't tell me to put a spear in your hand.
我还有其他方式 大人
There are other ways to serve, My Lord.
我现在可是王子了 你可得好好的——
I'm a prince now,and you'd do well--
我还有其他方式 王子殿下
There are other ways to serve, my prince.
比如？
Like what?
我们自由人 懂得
We know things,the Free people.
你们懂？
You know things?
懂什么？
Like what?
如何含垢忍辱？
How to eat dirt?
其他事情
Other things.
原始的事情
Savage things.
在外候命
Wait outside.
我总想尝尝
你那下面的滋味如何
I always wondered what you had under there.
这是有条件的
It comes at a price.
我没杀你 这就是条件
I'm not killing you. That's your price.
这条件我已经有了
I already had that.
除了你这不堪的生活
What do you want, then,
你还想要什么？
other than your miserable life?
所有自由人都渴望的——
What all free people want--
自由
my freedom.
只要你服侍的不错
Well, you shall have it, then.
你会得到的
But only if you serve me well.
－还好不是很深  －我还以为他们会杀了我
- It's not deep. - I thought they were going to kill me.
他们是这样想的
They thought so, too.
打我的那个人 他恨我
He hated me,the man who hit me.
从他的眼神中 我能看到憎恨
I saw it in his eyes. Hated me.
他从来没见过我
He never met me before,
可是他想伤害我
but he wanted to hurt me.
－他当然想  －为什么 为什么一个陌生人会——
- Of course he did. - Why? Why would a stranger--
你有他永远不会拥有的一切
you are everything he will never have.
你的马比他孩子吃的还好
Your horse eats better than his children.
不过现在无所谓了 他已经死了
It doesn't matter now. He's dead.
如果有面包的话 我会给他们的
I would have given them bread if I had it.
比起他们 我更憎恨国王
I hate the King more than any of them.
别说这些了
Don't say these things.
如果被不合适的人听见了——
If the wrong people hear you--
但是你不是什么不合适的人啊
But you're not the wrong people.
不要相信任何人
Don't trust anybody.
这样才比较安全
Life is safer that way.
你要去哪里？
And where are you going?
席恩王子让我带点东西给你
I have something for you from Prince Theon.
－是什么？  －我
- What? - Me.
他让我挨个伺候过来
He says I'm to make the rounds.
并为你们取暖
And keep you warm.
香料之王拒绝了我 他觉得我是个糟糕的投资对象
The Spice King refuses me because I'm a bad investment.
丝绸之王也不会支持我
The Silk King won't support me
因为他还要跟兰尼斯特做生意
because of his business with the Lannisters.
干嘛要得罪他最好的客户呢？
Why offend his best customer?
而黄铜之王愿意为我提供一艘船
And the Copper King offers me a single ship
条件是我得陪他睡一晚
on the condition that I lie with him for a night.
难道他觉得一艘船就能让我跟婊子一样出卖自己吗？
Does he think I will whore myself for a boat?
来到这个城市时 我一无所有
When I came to this city, I had nothing.
确实是一无所有
Truly nothing.
我只能睡在码头边
I slept by the docks.
若我能找到搬运工的工作 才能果腹
And when I could find work loading the ships, I would eat.
如果没有 连食物都是奢望
If not, I dreamed of food.
如今我是魁尔斯最富有的人
Today I am the richest man in Qarth.
你认为从贫困到富裕的路途
Do you think the path from poverty to wealth
始终是纯洁而荣誉的吗？
is always pure and honorable?
我做了很多事， 卡丽熙
I have done many things, Khaleesi,
很多会被正直的人所不齿的事情
that a righteous man would condemn.
但我并不后悔
And here I am, with no regrets.
守住城门 敲响警钟
Bar the gates. Ring the bells.
小心点 卡丽熙
Slowly, Khaleesi.
它们在哪儿？
Where are they?
我的龙在哪儿？
Where are my dragons?!
衣柜字幕组出品